

Profile

Hardworking and curious electrical engineer with a wide array of experiences. My love for learning, and solving problems and my diverse background in engineering, coding, and management make me versatile in any team. I'm willing to dive deep and engage wholeheartedly in captivating ventures.

Employment History

Head of the Regional Competence Center for Mechanical Engineering and Mechatronics - Establishment Phase at Technical School Čakovec

March 2022 — November 2023

- Actively engaged in the implementation of two EU projects (EBRD

 European Fund for Regional Development, ESF European Social
 Fund) valued at €7.5 million
- Spearheaded multiple project-based initiatives such as drafting procurement specifications, organization of events, educational visits, partnerships

Teacher of Electrical Group Subjects at Technical School Čakovec September 2018 — March 2022

- Conducted comprehensive lectures on various topics including microcontrollers, PLCs, embedded systems, automation, robotics, business communication and foundational electrical topics.
- Undertook roles such as Class Master, team leader for Renewable Energy Sources, and Chair of the school's Electrical Engineering Council

Head of International Projects and Sales Network at ENERGY PLUS

January 2016 — July 2018

- Supported top-tier international clients and presented the company at fairs
- Worked on LED lighting projects documentation and investment projects, emphasizing Energy Performance Contracting

Agency Director at Međimurska energetska agencija d.o.o.

January 2013 — January 2016

- Directed agency operations, resource management, growth strategies and successfully transformed the agency's financial standing toward complete self-sustainability.
- Managed multiple energy-focused projects and campaigns, promoting, and implementing energy efficiency and renewable energy adoption

Details

Croatia

00385992656398

mario.klobucaric@gmail.com

Links

Personal Page LinkedIn GitHub

Skills

Python

Python for Data Science & ML

VS Code

Jupyter Notebook

OpenAl API

Git/GitHub

Embedded

Arduino, Raspberry PI

C++

SQL

HTML & CSS

Dart&Flutter

REST APIs

Siemens Logo

Languages

Croatian

English

German

Hobbies

Reading: Technology, the Future, People, Mindset, Psychology, Personal Growth

Licensed Designer at DORS PROJEKT & ZG-PROJEKT

June 2007 — December 2012

- Designed electrical installations for various sectors, including "smart home" and photovoltaic plants.
- Designed electrical installations for highways, tunnels, and road lighting

Education

Faculty of Organization and Informatics, Varaždin

October 2017 — June 2018

- 56 ECTS
- Specialization: Teacher Education (Pedagogical/Psychological/Didactic/Methodical)

University Specialist of Strategic Entrepreneurship, 60 ECTS, Faculty of Economics, Zagreb

2009 - 2011

- Thesis: Leadership in Social Responsibility & Social Entrepreneurship
- GPA: 4.6/5

Graduate Electrical Engineer (Industrial Electronics), 274 ECTS, Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing, Zagreb

October 2000 — July 2005

- Thesis: Multichannel Receiver for Surface Electromyography
- GPA: 4.15/5

Natural Science and Mathematics Gymnasium, Čakovec

1996 — 2000

Awards: 1st (3x) & 3rd (3x) in County Mathematics Competitions (13-18 years)

Courses

Various online courses on topics: Python, Data Science, ML, Flutter and similar, Udemy

2019 - 2023

★ Personal projects

2019 - 2023

- Robotic arm system with Python GUI on Raspberry PI.
- Flutter app for OpenAI models: GPT Chat, Whisper, Dall-E.
- ComfortClick-based home automation with integrated security and adaptive heating (KNX & Modbus).
- Raspberry PI web server for environmental data visualization.
- 3D printed foldable drone with betaflight.